Meng Yang

Senior Software Engineer at Apple

Summary

Currently I am working for Apple's Graphics and Imaging group on the system level graphics infrastructure powering the next generation of OS X / iOS in Cuptertino, CA. Previously I spent 6 years with Microsoft in Redmond, WA and extensively worked on kernel level operating system rendering component through release cycles of Windows 7/8/8.1/10. My previous industry experience includes Senior Summer Analyst at Lehman Brothers in New York, NY (Fixed Income / Credit Analytics), and Software Engineer at Electronic Arts in Los Angeles, CA (Steven Spielberg's game project).

I received my M.S.E. and B.S.E. degrees in Computer Science from University of Pennsylvania, with minors in Mathematics and Fine Arts.

Programming: C++, C, Java

Computer Graphics: DirectX/Direct2D, HLSL / cg, OpengGL;

Physically-based Animation: Fluid Simulation, Particle System, Rigid-Body Simulation;

3D Packages: Maya, Mel, Maya API

Experience

Senior Software Engineer at Apple

October 2014 - Present

Hardware accelerated system level graphics and display infrastructure powering OS X / iOS.

Software Development Engineer II at Microsoft

August 2008 - October 2014 (6 years 3 months)

Hardware accelerated kernel level DirectComposition/Desktop Window Manager composition and animation engine powering Windows 8, 8.1 and 10

Senior Summer Analyst at Lehman Brothers

2008 - 2008 (1 year)

Fixed Income / Credit Analytics 05/2008 – 08/2008

• Designed and delivered grid-based interface for real-time cash analytics; scaled over 40 servers

Software Engineer at Electronic Arts

2006 - 2007 (2 years)

Software Engineer,

LMNO: Steven Spielberg's Game Project 05/2007 – 08/2007

- Shipped Maya plugin in C++ enabling complex 3D scene transfer from Maya to UnrealEngine3
- Revised initial framework for offline generating Ambient Occlusion maps in UE3

Software Engineer (Intern),

LMNO: Steven Spielberg's Game Project 05/2006 – 08/2006

- Developed Maya plugin in Mel manipulating Universal Capture facial animation data
- Post-processed CgFX hardware shaders (bump mapping, sepia and gamma correction)

Education

University of Pennsylvania

Master of Science in Engineering, Computer Science, 2007 - 2008

University of Pennsylvania

Bachelor of Science in Engineering, Computer Science, Mathematics, 2003 - 2007

Meng Yang

Senior Software Engineer at Apple



Contact Meng on LinkedIn